readingplus.com 2019-01-16

# Privacy Policy | Reading Plus

_Revised on May 24, 2018_

We at Taylor Associates Communications, Inc. (“Taylor Associates” or “we”) respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your privacy through our compliance with this policy.

This notice describes Taylor Associates’ policy for information we collect or that you may provide through our website, <https://www.readingplus.com/> (our “Website”), as well as our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing that information. Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. By accessing or using this Website, you agree to this privacy policy. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, you have the option to not access or use the Website.

 ** _Note to parents and students who use the Reading Plus application:_ This policy does not apply to our commercial online educational software products being provided to a school under the school’s agreement(s) with Taylor Associates (the “Reading Plus application”). The privacy policy for the Reading Plus application is available at [https://privacy.readingplus.com](https://privacy.readingplus.com/)**. 

#### What types of personal and non-personal information do we gather?

We gather information when you visit our Website or communicate with us through our Website.  The information we gather includes information by which you may be personally identified or other information defined as personally identifiable information under an applicable law (“personal information”) such as name, address, phone number, email address, grade level of students enrolling in courses, and shipping and billing information for orders (i.e., credit card number and expiration date). We may also record the types of product information you have requested.

Like many websites, we may also gather a variety of additional personal and non-personal information as you navigate through the Website including, but not limited to, your IP address (a unique number that identifies your access account on the Internet), domain and web browser information, technical information about your workstation or local area network, and information collected through cookies and other tracking technologies. We may track the page you visited before coming to our site, the page you link to when you leave, which of our pages you access, and how long you spend on each page. You can opt out of behavioral tracking on our Website and learn more about how we respond to web browser signals and other mechanisms that enable consumers to exercise choice about behavioral tracking by emailing us at info@readingplus.com.

#### How do we use the personal and non-personal information that we gather?

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including personal information, to present our Website and its contents to you, to provide you with information, products, or services that you request from us, for shipping, billing, and collection purposes, to respond to consumers’ requests, to provide consumers with special offers, to notify consumers of new product launches, to fulfill any other purposes for which you may provide information, and for internal business and marketing purposes. We may also use your information to contact you about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to use your information in this way, you may send an email to info@readingplus.com.  ** _ _**

It is our goal to retain any personal information we collect about you for only as long as we need it for the purposes described above. Accordingly, we will delete or otherwise dispose of your information when it is no longer needed, subject to any restrictions imposed by law.

#### What about cookies?

We receive and store certain types of information automatically through the use of “cookies.” Cookies are files that your web browser places on your computer’s hard drive. We use cookies to track your experience with the Website, to tell us whether you have visited the Website previously, to assist with login procedures for online courses, and to help us determine if you came from a particular link or banner advertisement. You may set your browser to reject cookies, but this will limit some functionality of the site.

#### Do we disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties?

We may disclose personal information that we collect or that you provide to representatives, contractors, service providers and other third parties we use to support our business or for any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information. We may also provide your personal information to our authorized sales representatives to assist with sales-related questions and inquiries. If you do not want us to disclose this information to our authorized sales representatives, you may send an email to info@readingplus.com or write to us using the contact information listed below. We will process your request promptly. We may also disclose aggregated information about our users and information that does not identify any individual without restriction.

Notwithstanding anything else in this policy, we may: (a) disclose personal information when required by a valid legal mechanism such as a search warrant, subpoena, or court order, or when we deem it necessary to protect the safety of site users, our employees or property; and (b) disclose personal information in the context of the sale of some or all of our assets, including sales in bankruptcy or in connection with liquidation events.

#### What about children’s privacy?

Our Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any information to the Website. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 on our Website. We also do not knowingly collect personal information from or about individual students on our Website. No student personal information may be provided to our Website. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 or a student without proper consent, we will promptly delete that information. If you believe we have inadvertently collected personal information of a child under 13 or a student on this Website without proper consent, please contact us at info@readingplus.com so that we may delete such data as soon as possible.

#### How are email links treated?

We use email links located throughout our Website to allow you to contact us directly with any questions or comments you may have. We read every message submitted to us and try to reply promptly to each one. The information contained in these messages is used to respond directly to your questions or comments. We may also use this information to improve the web site and learning programs.

#### Can I opt out of receiving communications from Taylor Associates?

Yes. If you do not wish to receive any communications, please email us or write to us using the contact information listed below. We will process your request promptly. Please be aware that you may receive another contact before your name removal takes effect. We regret any inconvenience this may cause.

#### Links

The Website may contain links to other websites. Taylor Associates is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites and this policy does not apply to information collected by any third party.   ** _ _**

#### How can I modify my personal information?

We believe it is important for you to be able to access whatever information we possess concerning you or your child, to the extent reasonably feasible and not unduly burdensome. If any such information is inaccurate and you wish to have it corrected, amended, or deleted, please email or write to us using the contact information listed below.

#### Will this policy change?

We reasonably expect that changes to our privacy policy will be needed over time. If at some future point there is a material change to this policy or to our information collection and usage practices that affects your personally identifiable information, we will notify you of the relevant change. We will provide such notice on this Website and also contact you via email, if we have collected your email address as part of your experience with our Website and/or products. We also will not make material changes to other policies or practices governing the use of personally identifiable information that are inconsistent with contractual requirements except as required by law. If you are concerned at any time about how your information is collected or used, please check our Website periodically to review our current privacy policy.

#### Security

We maintain administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed to protect your personal information and to help prevent unauthorized access, use, disclosure, and alteration of your personal information. However, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is completely secure and we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

#### Change of Control

If we sell or otherwise transfer part or the whole of Taylor Associates or our assets to another organization (e.g., in the course of a transaction like a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, liquidation), your information may be among the items sold or transferred. The buyer or transferee will be obligated to comply with the terms of our Privacy Policy under which the information was collected.

#### How do I contact the website?

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy, our information collection and use practices, or your dealings with this Website, you may contact us as follows:

  1. By email to [info@readingplus.com](mailto:info@readingplus.com)
  2. By mail to Privacy Officer, Taylor Associates Communications, Inc., 110 W. Canal St. Suite 301, Winooski, VT 05404
  3. By phone at 1-800-732-3758
